[Music]
he
w
[Music]
hello and welcome back to the ask AET
Show Episode 205 I hope you're all doing
great as always we're going to see who
all is in attendance right right now on
the live chat and in case you're not
aware I'm going to take questions from
the live chat only today so it's fully
interactive Fully live chat and let us
see who all is there I can see rudra
McLovin Arian Amisha Mishra hello
Illuminati Creek hi Vladimir abijit
CH suyog subu Jen crazy brain hello
Anish sankit vak Haim Haim Lala hello sh
Watsa feminist Slayer
Anish Anish Namaste an Pai aush Pand
Prasad Dalal Surak L
hello har Sharma vishwakarma s r omik
hello a a y Wang good evening Sati Chan
cost jwal sagya Sharma rinchan Karma
Namaste Mambo Mambo vihan pel Aditi
biplab Chan sha pedla
snea Siliguri yes
sh ramachandra namaha mystery
geopolitical du
Jo arpit D animes Cosmic gaming 7781 DBZ
Natsu sidhar sidhar Singh rajpurohit
utar Patel band panda NK Singh Rahul ter
J Singh threat Ripper Chun chra Matos F
from Belgium hello GK bujak Horseman and
who else do we have pram Aram yanii
space KGB agent yes ra chab chicks
chavda ad pilai K ragunath somit
mangalam tiari hello sbit Haram hello
from Manipur aramas gorov and lots of
other people an kup hello simple gold
Trader and I'm going to stop there okay
okay so I'm done uh greeting you all I
won't be able to greet you all
individually but thank you so much for
being on the live stream now let's get
with going the questions a lot is
happening in the world I think uh it was
in 2021 in the first geopolitics podcast
that I did with ranir aladia that I said
I said that this you know sometimes
nothing happens for decades in the world
and sometimes decade pass in decades
pass in years so right now we are in the
decade of tremendous geopolitical change
a lot is happening a lot is changing in
the world and we seen that almost on a
daily basis
we had a regime change a coup in
Bangladesh right next door there's stuff
brewing in Thailand there's stuff
Brewing everywhere there is stuff
brewing in the Ukraine conflict even
though it's a slow War Frozen conflict
kind of situation there is something or
the other happening lot so the point
is what's the questions that you have
okay yes J says what do you think about
the KGB uh the KGB no longer exists or
maybe it exists in a different form it
was one of the most capable
organizations spy agencies ever
worldwide it was the USSR spy agency and
today you have a something else that
exists in its stead in Russia so very
capable Elite spy agency
tremendous okay now the question is what
other questions do we
have Ajay nagar talks about something
apart from geopolitics of sence of
History I want to focus on my studies
but I'm always but why am I always
attracted to women how to overcome this
just because she's beautiful why I feel
attraction nature Etc listen it's it's
part of life it's natural it's normal
you got to well you got to deal with it
there's nothing you can do about it it's
just there's nothing abnormal or unusual
about it but when it comes to studies
when it comes to getting ahead in career
in life you have to compartmentalize
things you get attracted to women
wonderful fantastic it means you're a
healthy person you keep that a side when
you're studying you've got to learn how
to deal with these things when you're
reading a book you cannot think about
something else so do one thing at a time
people talk about multitasking I think
multitasking doesn't really work people
who claim they're good at multitasking
are actually you know uh not being very
honest you can't multitask the human
brain the human mind is such that you
can only focus on one thing at a time so
when you're studying focus on studies
switch off all the
distractions and it's it's a skill you
have to acquire how to focus on
something for an extended period of time
you can use hacks like tell yourself I'm
going to study for 10 minutes 10 minutes
I'm only going to study and you keep a
timer with an alarm clock or whatever
and when you're done get a walk around
and think about women if you want then
go back to studying studying after five
minutes so you got to find hacks and all
that but it's okay nothing nothing wrong
with
that okay zubon ising says the ongoing
peace talks between the government of
India and the Naga insurgents there are
rumors that there are benefits if you're
in one of the factions and youngsters
are planning on joining it
okay I will not comment about
rumors
um there's there's a lot happening in
India's Far East Manipur nagaland Etc
Manipur nagaland are part of the same
area and obviously you have mizoram and
you have across the border the situation
in Burma Civil War and it's all being
fermented by a foreign power and other
foreign powers also have interest in
this and if we know histo if in case
you're not aware historically the Far
East of India so the so-called Northeast
you had insurgencies everywhere in every
single state there were multiple
Insurgent groups in every single state
in the 1960s prime minister Indira
Gandhi was forced to bomb mizoram to
deal with the insurgence that's how bad
it got in mizoram and the same happened
in every other state in India's Far East
and much of this was was encouraged and
supported by foreign powers China was
very much part of this in the 1960s '70s
20th century even until recently they
may still be involved in that okay I I
assure you they would have been involved
in all of this at various points in time
including in more recent times let's
just put it that way uh now obviously we
want the situation to go back to normal
we want the people of this region to get
everything that they deserve as Indian
citizens and all the benefits all the
everything and most of the problems that
have happened in the region are a
because of the stupid idiotic moronic
half-brained policies of the government
of India in the 20th century and some of
that has continued in the 21st century
also that's a and b interference by
Foreign Nations who understood that
there was a big opportunity because of
the stupidity of the government of India
okay in the 20th century onwards so they
they armed they send money and arms and
ammunition and material support and
whatnot to these Insurgent outfits
separatist outfits Insurgent outfits
whatever you want to call them and
that's all that happened so today you
have the legacy of all these uh events
all of these things that happened in the
past you still have the continuing
Legacy of that in the Far East of India
so there's going to be ongoing peace
talks now I don't know about the rumors
I will not talk about the rumors because
there's no way of verifying if whether
it's right or right or not then you
should not encourage rumors so I will
not comment about that because I don't
know if it's true or not probably it's
not true and I'm sure the government of
India understands what are the risks
involved in the fact that we have to be
completely
fair and the nation comes first always
so I hope that things go well going
forward and these issues are
resolved geopolitical dues says there's
political turmoil and unrest in Thailand
there is the same in Burma in Nepal and
in Bangladesh what's
happening you are pretty observant my
dear friend so let's let's see what's
happening right let's let's take a look
at the map of the region and what all is
going on in the region off late because
a lot is happening in this region of
late you have India that's where I
suppose many of the viewers who are
watching right now live in case you're
not from India well welcome and I hope
this helps you understand what's
happening so you have India here which
dominates the Indian Ocean region okay
now to the west of India you have
Pakistan in Pakistan there was a coup in
2022 that nobody really regards as a
coup Imran Khan that the elected prime
minister was overthrown and and the
puppet was put in place even Imran Khan
was more or less a puppet because the
real power in Pakistan is the the
Pakistani armed forces the military who
are beholden to foreign powers they are
essentially a mercenary Force so you
were a coup in 2022 in Pakistan and
Imran Khan was Pro China was thrown out
and a very strongly Pro us regime has
come to power in Afghanistan as you know
the Taliban have taken over this also
happened couple of years ago which year
was it 21 22 probably somewhere around
that time I forget my memory doesn't
always
uh you know the the point is Taliban has
come to power they are a pro us Force
strangely enough okay strangely enough
they are on the US payroll allegedly
there is that so to the west of India
you have that happening Iran the Middle
East the West Asia region is always in
conflict and there's a lot happening
right now Sri Lanka you had the Raja
pakas who had to leave the country and
this country was nearly bankrupted by
them and by Chinese involvement Etc you
have that and to the east to the north
of India you you to the northeast of
India you have Nepal the actual
Northeast of India Nepal and Nepal well
there's always you know right now the
situation in Nepal is such that the
political system the political class is
very strongly pro-china and uh they have
ensured the education system the media
all of that portrays China as as nicer
as as better for for the Nepal's
interest compared to India so there is
that entire narrative that's prevalent
in NE Nepal right now uh then Bhutan
there are Chinese incursions there is a
lot of Chinese pressure on Bhutan to
give up territory especially close to
the Siliguri Corridor
Etc in Bangladesh we had a regime change
and the Americans have installed a pro
us puppet regime in place uh our bang my
Bangladeshi few viewers who are watching
if they are will strongly disagree with
what I say that's fine I understand the
Bangladeshi perspective I understand the
fact that the Bangladeshi people regard
this as the restoration of democracy
Etc uh Bangladesh is a is a nation
that's truly conflicted it's conflicted
between two very strongly opposing
forces first of all is is is is its
Bengali identity which goes back
thousands of years and the second is the
fact that the majority of the population
90 person plus is Muslim so there is
this conflict between these two
identities the Islamic identity and the
Bengali identity and there's a lot to
unpack there which I'll not go into and
then to India's North we have Chinese
occupied Tibet which is kind of well
stable and to India's
East you have Burma Myanmar which is in
the throws of a devastating Civil War uh
and the objective is to install Pro us
ra you know uh governments in parts of
Burma overthrow the B government which
is kind of pro China and to create an
artificial Nation called cookie land an
artificial Christian Nation out of parts
of Burma parts of bangadesh and part
parts of India nagaland Manipur sorry
not nagaland but Manipur and mizoram de
facto Christian Nation whether it's
officially recognized or not doesn't
matter and then so you have a civil war
in Burma and then you have what looks
like a new regime change operation in
Thailand so the current uh prime
minister has been disqualified by the
constitutional
court or whatever they call it and now
it looks like the shatas will come back
to Power so that's something that is in
process in progress as we speak right
now a lot is happening a lot is
happening but what you will find is that
there is generally a pro US Government
In tha in Thailand you generally have
that uh you have Pro US government in
the Philippines Pro US government in
Taiwan Pro US government in Malaysia
Indonesia Burma will be taken care of
eventually by the Americans Bangladesh
is now Pro
us so what it does is is kind of it it
en circles India now India is not
anti-us India is not hostile to the US
India is simply a very large independent
Sovereign
Nation that's what India is and the
Americans want India to take
sides in the world they want us they
want India to take the side of the US
when it comes to the Russia Ukraine
conflict India has stayed neutral India
has pursued its own
interests uh the the Americans would
like India to participate in the
sanctions against Russia which would be
very bad for Russia if India did that
but India has
refused the US wants India to
participate in various actions against
China India would not want that to
happen India would like to have a
reasonably good relationship with China
despite all the Chinese provocations on
the border and all that so that's the
conundrum India faces so the entire
region around India is kind of every
single nation in the region is either
occupied by somebody else as in the case
of Tibet or it's a proxy of somebody
else Pakistan is a US proxy Afghanistan
is a US proxy Sri Lanka you could say is
a US proxy the Maldives are a Chinese
proxy Bangladesh us proxy Nepal Chinese
proxy Bhutan is in Indian
protectorate then you have Burma which
is in the state of Civil War it used to
be a Chinese proxy it could soon have
multiple Nations formed out of Burma
many of them Pro us and so on you get
the point that's what's happening that's
a big overview of the region of what's
happening in the region
okay okay aksh Dillon says what about
the Iran Israel conflict with Will Iran
go to war with Israel okay so let's re
let's revisit that conflict so there's a
lot to unpack there also historically
speaking well it all starts in the 1970s
1979 there's the Islamic revolution in
Iran comes back to Power and the regime
of the
ayas like the West likes to say comes to
power in Iran this is a strongly
anti-west regime well aah Ki was you
know he had taken refuge in in France in
Paris I think it's Paris France for many
years in Exile he was in Exile and then
he comes back to Power this is a
strongly anti-west uh regime that's what
the West says uh the I think the
perspective of the Iranian government is
that they are not anti-west they simply
want to be left
alone uh but yeah everybody has a
different perspective but the overall
strongly um you know the dominant
narrative the media narrative that you
will see in India everywhere else is
that Iran has a strongly anti-west
government and India is a state and and
Iran is a strongly anti-west government
and Iran is a state sponsor of terrorism
well do you remember the 1980s 1990s Etc
2000s even 20 T there was Pakistani
terrorism in India the question is who
was supporting that who was sponsoring
that it was the US wasn't it let's call
us PID a spade so what does that make
the
US I think you can guess what it makes
them anyway so you have Iran which is
anti-us the Americans have imposed all
kinds of sanctions on Iran which has
devastated the Iranian Persian economy
and you've had a lot of hostility
between Iran and Israel the the Iranians
call US the US Shan abor the great Satan
and they regard Israel as either a
servant or a master of of the US I don't
know which which perspective they have
but there you have it so Iran says that
the Zionist regime like they say doesn't
have the right to exist they want to
wipe Israel off the map of the world now
obviously Israel will not feel very
happy about that right and Israel
obviously has the right to self-defense
correct um so Israel is also a very
proactive Nation just like Iran Iran is
a geopolitically ambitious Nation it
punches way above its weight it has
proxies in Iraq it has proxies in Syria
it has Proxes in Yemen it has proxies in
Lebanon even in Gaza West Bank
Etc so Israel obviously feels kind of
worried about that and the Israel is a
very good power projection capabilities
they also have a nuclear Arsenal an
Undeclared nuclear Arsenal an Undeclared
nuclear power in Israel and the US have
over time hit out at the Iranians the
the Iranian General kasum suani was
taken out he was assassinated through a
drone strike missile strike when he was
in Bagdad U when Mr Trump was in
power then uh a couple of uh high
ranking Iranian generals were
assassinated in Damascus
by by an Israeli air strike or missile
strike and recently the head of Hamas Mr
what's his name I forget the
name he was assassinated in tan in tan
in the capital of Iran and the Iranians
have blamed Israel for this the Iranians
uh had a few weeks ago launched a
massive drone and missile strike on
Israel that was mostly
ineffective and now after this
assassination of uh the Hamas the head
of Hamas um the question is what does
Iran do about this will they retaliate
will they in what way will they
retaliate will they go to war now the
point is how can Iran go to war with
Israel you see the distance between the
two Nations uh if you do a very rough
and quick measurement of the distance
between the two Nations it's about 900
kilometers you know straight line so
roughly 1,00 kilometers roughly 900
kilometers the distance between two
between the two Nations Iran does not
have a powerful Air Force the kind of
air force that can launch air strike
successfully and come back on Israel so
they can launch ballistic missile
strikes cruise missile strikes or drone
strikes
but that last time it happened was quite
ineffective no high value targets were
destroyed no significant damage happened
in Israel because of the Israeli iron
iron doome system which is which is a
missile defense drone defense system so
how does Iran go to war with Israel even
if it wants to Israel can certainly
launch air strikes in Iran they have a
very good Air Force Iran doesn't have
that so the question is what does Iran
do the only way they can successfully
hit out a
Israel is through either covered
operations or through proxies like Hamas
hisbah or the
hutis or in some other way
assassinations of some kind or or cyber
attacks or or whatever so Iran doesn't
have the kind of options that Israel has
and the question is what about the
nuclear
angle well I believe Iran could have
sufficient file material buy today for a
few uh basic nuclear warheads fishion
Warheads you know tactical Nuclear Wars
I don't know 50 kiloton or so maybe
maybe that's too much maybe 20 kiloton
yield so maybe they have sufficient f
file material for maybe a handful of
nuclear warheads but if they do have
that then those nuclear warheads are
precious and you don't want to use
Warheads nuclear warheads ever
in war so then what does Israel what
does Iran do so I think the options are
limited when it comes to Iran the uh
non-traditional options non-conventional
options they have a lot but traditional
War conventional War options are limited
when it comes to Iran Israel has more
options so that's where we are so the
region the west Asia region will remain
in turmoil the region will remain
restive I hope they it doesn't progress
and escalate Beyond a point but that's
the situation and the other other
nations in the region don't want this
this sort of warlike situation you know
Saudi Arabia Arabia desires progress
they don't want war they want peace in
the region so does Oman so does the
UAE uh and it will be beneficial for
everybody if there is peace in the
region but the region has always been
artificially kept on the boil so that is
the situation right now so right now I
don't foresee a major escalation major
escalation in the
conflict you may see some kind of
escalation you may see some kind of
hostilities and back and forth but
hopefully not full scale War I think the
probability of that is kind of kind of
overall less right now right
now interesting question by mclevin
what's happening in the International
Space Station are the astronauts live at
risk how will they come
back yeah yeah so there are two
astronauts right now on the
International Air space station the ISS
is uh the space station that has been in
orbit for best part of two decades I'd
say and it's in orbit around the Earth
at an altitude of what 200 300
kilometers roughly above the surface
roughly if I'm not
mistaken and
it's typically there's always somebody
there the recent astronauts who visited
there are there two people one is Sunita
Williams and the other person I forget
the name okay I'll I'll remember the
Indian name naturally so that lady
Sunita Williams is is of Indian origin
partially at least and she's there and
there's another another astronaut there
with her two of them own the
ISS and they uh they reached the ISS a
few I don't know couple of a few months
ago on a boing
spacecraft now this spacecraft developed
problems there's a leakage of fuel or
helium or something and there are some
other issues with the spacecraft so it's
not safe they were supposed to return to
Earth on the same
spacecraft and this was happened
supposed to happen several weeks
ago and uh the spacecraft is is not in
good condition it's not safe for them to
return on that spacecraft so the
spacecraft is docked on one of the ports
okay one of the docks of the
International Space
Station and as far as I know the ISS has
two two docks so two spacecraft can be
docked at the same time so in one one of
the one of the docs you have the uh
boing spacecraft which is not functional
which is dangerous you cannot use that
so the option is you need you can send
another spacecraft to dock with the ISS
and bring the astronauts back or you can
have a transfer one batch of astronauts
comes in and these two who have been
stuck there can go back on the same
spacecraft so there is the possibility
that this Boeing spacecraft may get may
get stuck there for a very long period
of time maybe indefinitely maybe because
it needs they have installed some kind
of software update that makes it
impossible for it to be undocked without
a person being present
inside but if you undock with a person
inside that person has to return to
Earth and it's not
safe so you can't Ma you you can't
remotely undock it and have it crash
into the ocean or whatever you need
somebody in the spacecraft to be able to
unlock it that's the kind of situation
you are in right now so that is the
spacecraft and then these two
individuals the two astronauts are stuck
there and it looks like they'll be stuck
there until the next year this was
supposed to be couple of weeks Mission
maybe two three weeks the mission was
supposed to be brief they are there
indefinitely they may be able to return
only next year so I don't think their
lives are in danger their lives are not
in danger there is probably enough food
oxygen all that on the space station to
sustain them
indefinitely um you know
supplies but yeah they're stuck there so
if any of them had plans of what to do
in October November December whatever
all those plans have gone on haire but
hopefully they return safe as soon as
they can but this raises questions about
boing what on Earth has happened to
boing it was one of the great companies
that the
US
uh threw up
right one of the Great American
companies boing they made so many
wonderful aircraft and spacecraft and
all that and what is happening they have
taken a real real they're in Decline
booing the standards have slipped
multiple aircraft crashes multiple
issues with aircraft quality issues
cropping up
everywhere doors falling off all kinds
of
problems aircraft plummeting at you know
a couple of thousand meters in a few
seconds all kinds of terrible issues
with boing and now this spacecraft which
is stuck there a spacecraft that could
if you try to fly in it it may kill
human beings terrible terrible something
is deeply wrong with with boing it's a
cultural shift I think what's happened
with boing is that MBA types have taken
over the leadership of
boing when you have a company like boing
which is an engineering company that
produces that that produces aircraft
manufactures aircraft and manufactures
spacecraft you need engineers in the
leadership not MBA types who are
concerned with sales and marketing
so when you're concerned when your full
focus is on sales and marketing and you
sideline the engineers this is what
happens and then you have other non
engineering issues that take precedence
so that's I think this is a cautionary
tale for any company what not to do in
what direction not to
go so that yeah there you have it that's
boing
okay Theus says what's the real agenda
behind the upcoming VIs of un uh
Personnel to Bangladesh the very simple
agenda behind this upcoming V visit is
to legitimize the government the the
government that's taken power in
Bangladesh okay this is a an
undemocratically uh formed government
okay this government has not come to
power through an election so they call
that guy Mr Muhammad Yos they call him
the interim or taker or whatever prime
minister and uh all that so the agenda
so it's clear that this government has
not come to power through any Democratic
process what happened in Bangladesh is
this is essentially the Bangladeshi
version of the Euro Maan coup that
happened in Ukraine in 2014 10 years
later 10 years on this happens in
Bangladesh so the un's the the agenda is
to legitimize the government it's to
give the UN blessing thing that this is
a good government democracy blah blah
blah human rights Etc all taken care of
that's the agenda very simple and the UN
obviously is
well when it comes to any multilateral
multilateral
organization the organization is
typically
controlled essentially owned by the most
powerful Nation within that's the US
so uh Summit state M says I want a
peaceful unification with bat um I
expect you're talking about you you're
from Nepal I would imagine okay but I'm
also afraid that aror will lose a sagur
MAA to China I desperately want a great
and powerful Nation glory to Mother SRAM
bhat yeah so look yeah I understand the
sentiment I also understand the the
the the
fear so right now uh
sagur MAA which the Indians and
westerners call Mount
Everest is kind of on the border between
Nepal and Tibet China is occupied Tibet
so the northern face if you if you want
to climb the mountain from the northern
phas you to take Chinese visa you to be
on Chinese occupied Tibetan territory
and then do it from there the other way
is to go through this traditional route
which is from
Nepal so the fear that the Smit
statement is expressing is that if Nepal
and India bat are reunited in the future
then Nepal may end up losing sagur mat
to
China so
uh the the only long-term solution is
for Tibet to be free eventually whenever
that happens it won't happen any anytime
in the future once Tibet both Desh is
free again of any foreign occupation
then that fear doesn't exist anymore
because Tibet is part part of
our uh extended
cultural sphere of influence so Tibetan
culture is nothing but a local version
of of Indian culture with a lot of
enrichment from Tibetan history and the
tibet's ancient past
itself um so if as long as Tibet is
under foreign occupation this fear will
exist this fear will exist
so the solution is for for Tibet to be
free of occupation that's all that's all
it is uh and obviously whenever this
happens in the future that bat Nepal and
whatever else there's a reunification it
should happen when India has a has a
bhartia government and a Bara
Constitution right now it is I don't
know if the people of Nepal want to be
under a secular Constitution the secular
Constitution that India has right now
right now bhat is India and India is a
secular State a Hindu phobic apad State
I don't
think
so it should happen in the future when
things are better in India and Barat
reclaims the status of a civilization
state is opposed to a simple nation
state the way it is right
now ishan Singh says why do Western
people really hate Indians oh look
why do it's not like everybody in the
west hates Indians okay there are
sensible people everywhere in the world
but they are generally in a minority the
over overall see overall what's
happening right now is that India is
growing India is growing for the first
time in a thousand years essentially
India was smashed and and humiliated for
a thousand years the Millennium of
humiliation the Chinese have this
Narrative of a century of humiliation by
the West Well India bhat has undergone a
millennial of humiliation and that
Millennium of humiliation
was under two foreign occupations one
was the turky occupation the second was
the European occupation mainly the
British occupation and this will end
only when bhat completely properly
decolonizes and we are not decolonized
right now so we are essentially
still enduring the Millennium of
humiliation now what's happened in the
past couple of decades is that India has
started growing economically India is
finally showing signs of coming close to
realizing its actual potential what is
India's potential historically we know
that India was the world's largest
economy India was the world's largest
economy for the majority of history for
the maximum part of known
history a thousand years ago India
accounted for at least a third of the
entire world's GDP so we are again
finally starting to climb take baby
steps towards reaching that that status
reclaiming that status of the world's
largest economy now that is something
that the existing Powers would not be
happy
with because it would mean that this
nation that was nearly destroyed the
civilization that still refuses to die
is now Reviving itself and it will soon
surpass the West Will the west like it
they won't like so when it comes to the
Western media they have this very strong
anti-india narrative that is spun all
the time and there was an significant
uptick upsurge of this after February 22
after the Russian ukra invasion of
Ukraine which India refused to
condemn so then this entire narrative
started being spun and all kinds of
experts started weighing in portraying
the current Indian government as fascist
and authoritarian and they have been
portraying India's democracy as
something that is backsliding India is
not a proper democracy y because we are
not pro
West I sometimes I appear on various
news channels like Republic and I get
you get lectured by
by by individuals from friendly
countries in those debates they lecture
us that we need to be more proest Etc it
is good for us and so on so we are not
doing that we are a genuinely Sovereign
Nation and we are refusing
to to become to part
participate or to become a Pawn on
somebody else's chess
board and that's why there is this very
strong anti there is a strong anger
against India in the US in the west
that's why they are they are creating
this narrative in the media and when
this media this narrative is created
there's also this other narrative that
is created that that wants that seeks to
portray India is a very backward
misogynistic dirty all that you know
country they want to p Hinduism as
something that's that's backward that is
evil that is misogynistic
patriarchal and so on so whatever
objectives you can you know
apply so this narrative is created in
the west and then the common people of
the West they simply go along with that
they believe what whatever the media
tells them most people are like sheep
most people even in India look the the
true quality of of a nation is
determined by the 0.1% the top 0.1%
99.9% of of the people are typically
going to be docile and they will go
ahead go along with the standard
narrative that is preached that is that
is professed by the professors the
education system the textbooks the media
and all that so they go along with that
and they've been conditioned they've
been brainwashed into having these
knee-jerk reactions so if somebody says
something that goes against what's
written in the the textbooks they'll
call that person a conspiracy theory
it's a knee-jerk reaction typical
standard they apply tags and labels so
most people are like this in India in
the west everywhere and that's why in
the west because this media narrative is
created because the education system
Port as India is a very backward country
Etc so all most people absorb this and
they genuinely believe that India is a
backward and bad country and that's what
you see on social media and that's why a
lot of Western people have these
negative
feelings and towards India negative
perception of India and then when they
see that India despite being such
apparently such a backward at such a
country is doing well it is launching
spacecraft to the Moon to Mars its
economy is growing it's about to become
the third largest econom economy in the
world a lot of anger is expressed how
dare you despite being being so backward
dirty blah blah blah how dare you
progress how dare dare you believe that
they you can surpass the West that's the
anger that you see hope that makes
sense
um okay let us take some other
questions tanai Chandra says what are
your views on the UK riots do you see
the arrival of a new crusade in
England uh the UK riots are a natural
expression or natural reaction to what's
being
done to the to the indigenous native
people of England and over all of the
West so look
I at one level I kind of feel sorry for
the people of the UK and the West I know
they have destroyed our nation they've
tried their best to destroy our nation
but I don't blame the common people for
that
it's the it's the government that's
tried to do that in the past the English
government the British government the
monarchy the British Raj and even today
they seek
to they seek to uh prevent India's
growth prevent India's rise delay
India's growth the governments do that
and there is a very strong anti- indan
narrative in the academic system in the
Academia in the media Etc and that's why
Mo a lot of westerners have a very
strong ly negative perception of India
despite all of
that at at some level I feel sorry for
the people of the UK the people of
Europe the people of the US
they the demographics of their nations
are being re-engineered and there is
nothing the people can do about
it okay so there is this big influx
yearly day monthly weekly daily of
immigrants of legal
immigrants from certain parts of the
world whether it's West Asia or
Afghanistan or or or parts of
Africa they are typically military age
men and they come without their families
they come there are there are hardly any
women or children so when you have
families that are coming in Legally
illegally whatever that means that those
people are refugees they're trying to
escape a bad situation from wherever
they come from but when it is military
age men who are immigrating illegally or
legally that's not an immigration that's
that's an
invasion so what Europe is seeing what
the UK has been seeing for the for
decades what the UK has been seeing for
decades and what Europe is seeing now is
an invasion a demographic
Invasion and
these Invaders let's say are given K the
blanch do whatever you want the cops
won't touch
you organize in any way you want unleash
violence on the
natives unleash all kinds of atrocities
on the natives on their women Etc the
cops won't touch but if the natives
fight back the cops will unleash
brutalities on the natives that's the
situation So eventually there's going to
be a reaction to that and that's what we
saw in the UK riots uh but uh there's
going to be no Crusade there's going to
be nothing the West is doomed
demographically the West is doomed
unless I mean even if you stop the you
put a hard stop full stop today
immediately on the illegal immigration
there's millions of these people in the
west
already imagine the logistical Nightmare
and challenge it is to deport millions
and millions of people would take
years would take a decade
plus unless you are as efficient as the
Germans have in the past alleged to have
been
but even then
it's it's it's almost impossible to do
it in a short period of time to the West
is
doomed a new demography is going to
arise in the west it's in the process of
of
arising and whatever white supremacy Etc
people may have had in their minds all
that will disappear because the white
race won't exist soon by the end of this
Century um so I think the native
cultures in the west are doomed the
native religion well not native but the
supposedly native religion Christianity
seems to be doomed in the west but it
may rise in India and in the East okay
because that's India is being targeted
right now for large scale industrial
scale conversion to Christianity in
various parts of India in the Far East
of India in Punjab in the south of India
essentially everywhere
everywhere so that's what's happening in
in England in the UK in the West I think
eventually I don't see too much of Hope
for the
West
right Arian tiari says despite being so
powerful why does the US tolerate Cuba
in Venezuela countries like these they
don't seem to be too friendly with the
US in the past years yeah good
question
so the US has imposed since the 60s no
even before that so since Fidel Castro
came to power the Americans imposed from
that time onwards the Americans have
imposed sanctions on Cuba crippling
sanctions debilitating sanctions the
Cubans still drive cars from the 1950s
you know that so tremendous sanctions on
Cuba and Cuba is completely under
control there was a brief period of time
when the Cubans Cuba became a problem
there was in the' 60s the Cuban Missile
Crisis but since then everything has
been fine so Cuba is completely crippled
completely under control what is there
to tolerate obviously they'll tolerate
it there will be intolerance only if
Cuba dares to uh get off the reservation
or or you know not stay its Lane Cuba is
completely under control when it comes
to
Venezuela Venezuela again it's economy
was crushed and destroyed by us
sanctions and now they are completely
harmless
and the Americans are again now buying
oil from Venezuela the Venezuela is
cooperating so why would you not
tolerate that they may have a regime
that doesn't like you very much but they
have no option they have no choice but
to obey and do what the Americans want
so why will the Americans not tolerate
please understand this the world is a
little bit more nuanced than black and
white Dubai is completely under control
and if the Americans decide if the
Americans desire they can flatten Cuba
tomorrow morning and the same with
Venezuela you most people have
absolutely no understanding of the
incredible might of the US
military you have absolutely no
understanding of how powerful the US
military is they can flatten Cuba
tomorrow morning if they wish they can
flatten Venezuela tomorrow morning if
they wish they have that
power so overall despite having the
power actually they being very nice and
of course they everything is is under
control so what's the problem so
understand that that you may have a
regime a government that's not friendly
but as long as you are under control and
you don't pose any genuine problems
they're going to tolerate you as long as
they get what they
want sidhant says many geopolitical
experts have hinted that the UK is going
to split okay I don't know who these
experts are but uh if you were to ask me
eventually the UK May split the United
Kingdom is made up of Scotland Northern
Ireland Wales and England and Scotland
has historically hated the English Wales
has historically fought the English and
the Irish despise the English okay but
the English they conquered the world
much of the world and they've conquered
their home region so if you go to
Scotland today
most Scots people don't even speak
Scottish anymore you go to Ireland today
most Irish people speak English very few
of them speak the native Irish language
how many Welsh people speak the Welsh
language so the the the British have
done a very good job of of subduing the
region and uh but if if uh in the future
it may so happen look no no map is
permanent all these lines on the map
they are all subject to change so you
have British occupied Northern Ireland
that eventually I would imagine will uh
reunify with the rest of the Island
Ireland I expect that sometime in the
future if there is a little bit of Pride
left among the Scottish people they will
once again in the future push for
independence from the from the English
so it may happen
but as of today the major hegemonic
power in the world is the United States
and all alterations to the map of the
world will happen only with their
blessing so if they feel that for some
reason it's okay to split Scotland from
UK then they will give the blessing and
it will happen but unless but if they
don't give their blessing it won't
happen so that's the that's the caveat
right
MRI Krishna says can I pursue
archaeology in India I want to support
my family through my favorite subject
but is it
possible look if you are the only person
who can is in a position to support your
family then I would say don't go for
archaeology look if if you study
archaeology um first of all I don't know
how many universities offer Arch a
degree in archaeology bachelor's degree
M master's degree you would generally in
the Indian context need at least a
master's degree to do well in a career
so where do you get a master's degree in
archology I would imagine the sayir ra
University in Boda
vodra probably offers a master's degree
in archaeology I'm not sure of how many
other universities offer that so first
of all there is that so you would need
to apply there get accepted then
complete the degree um there is that
first of all and then once you have the
degree
what's the Outlook career outlook for
archaeology in India I'm not sure
there's only one real organization that
does archology in India which is the ASI
the ASI is run by bureaucrats and the
ASI is a very moribund and Mal
performing organization institution from
my perspective they will disagree I'm
sure but to join the ASI I'm not sure
what is the route how do you enter the
ASI do you have to
do the I what's the exam
upsc and you give the elective as the as
the preference is ASI I'm not sure how
it is so you'll have to figure it
out but let's say you become you join
the ASI what kind of salary will you get
you'll get a government salary
government salaries are stable you have
a job for the rest of your life and and
you have a pension after you retire but
it's never a high paying job so is it
enough to to support your family not
sure about that it depends on depends on
so many factors that I'm not aware of so
you have to consider all these things
that's what I can tell you that's the
best I can that's the best answer I can
offer you without knowing your specific
circumstances your academic track track
record whether you will be able to to
obtain admission in an archaeology
program once you get your degree will
you be able to get into the ASI or or
any other organization there's so many
parameters and factors that I cannot see
right now so it's it's a judgment call
that you will have to make based on all
these
factors um so yeah that's what I can say
all the best I hope you do really well
and you get what you genuinely
desire
okay fre ramachandra namaha says as a
student it's very difficult for me to
study after knowing the history was fake
and biased what to do
what I did all my entire student life I
knew it even as a kid I knew it because
I have this
very very naughty tendency to read stuff
that read books that were not part of
the
curriculum so I used to read a lot and I
knew I knew that everything they're
teaching us is substandard and it's
wrong I knew the education system was
was terrible it was a waste of my time I
knew that and every single day every
single hour I had
to I had to
somehow because you had to get your
degree Etc right you there's no choice
so you have to memorize mug up this
nonsensical garbage that is served up in
these textbooks you know it's
substandard you know it's bad you know
it is Absolut it's going to give you
absolutely no value going forward but
you have to memorize it and you have to
write exactly that in your exams that is
something you have to do if you have to
get a
degree so you have no choice my dear
friend I know it's all fake and biased
so what you
would have to do is unfortunately mug it
up study
it write the exam and then give your
give give yourself permission to forget
it
all that's that's what I can say there's
no choice right now the education system
doesn't give the Indian education system
system doesn't give students a choice
you simply have to do this if you want
to get a degree and without a degree you
don't get a job in this country so
that's where you are uh so my point is
you have to be realistic and practical
sometimes you have
to like what's that book eat that frog I
don't know who who was it that wrote the
book eat that frog the the premise of
the book is that every every day in the
morning the moment you wake up make up
the most difficult task and finish it
off then everything is easier for you so
you have to do unpleasant things
sometimes not sometimes often times in
life that's what you will see throughout
your life so just do it that's what I
would
say Tas says new discovery of human
remains in harana that dates back to
8,000 BC 10,000 years before today will
the West finally accept that Arian
Invasion picnic tourism theory is false
the West will never accept anything uh
and I don't know what these human
remains are I've not seen the the news
I've not read the articles if there are
any research papers or reports of there
are any I have no idea but let's say you
find human remains in harana which date
back to 8,000 BC well you would need to
analyze those remains do a genetic
analysis and figure out what kind of
population and genetic lineages these
remains represent then you can talk
about the Arian Invasion myth or
whatever so uh without knowing any of
that I can't say just because you
discovered remains somewhere of a
certain time period doesn't mean that a
theory or certain theory is falsified or
proven
so it's it's too early to say so I
cannot pass any judgment without reading
about this in
detail uh but let's say let us say
hypothetically that these
remains what what will they show they
will show a lineage that it be similar
to present day modern Indian lineages or
maybe they'll show something else I
don't know so I think um it's too early
to to comment about this and because
I've not seen the the news not read
about this I can't say anything about
it but whatever happens the West will
never agree they will never accept that
the Aran Invasion theory is false
they'll simply keep on spinning the
narrative
okay uh geopolitical dub says the US has
South Korea and Japan but why are they
not able to do regime change in North
Korea or they don't want to do just to
pressurize South Korea and
Japan uh no they would I'm sure want to
have a regime change in North Korea and
had to have democracy in North Korea but
North Korea is firmly under the it has a
firm uh support and unconditional
support of China and China is powerful
enough in this region and North Korean
government regime whatever you want to
call it is in firm control of the
country and that's why they're not able
to do anything if North Korea was all
alone without the support of China the
Americans would do regime change
tomorrow morning but because the Koreans
have the North Koreans have Chinese
support that's why the Americans are
unable to do
that rudra says in terms of war in term
of
Wars how far are we behind the us and
China in Ai and advanced chips like
h100 could the US form a one world
government with AI surpassing the
nuclear problem tough
times how far are we behind first of all
in terms of wars in terms of military
might we are no comparison to the us and
we are overall in terms of hard power
about onethird that of China so China is
essentially three times more powerful
than India overall that is simply a fact
you got to accept that when it comes to
the US the US is
approximately 20 times more powerful
than
India 18 to 20 times more powerful than
India way more powerful okay so there is
no comparison between the US and India
the US is order it's like not not an
order of magnitude but like 20 times
more powerful yeah that's an order of
magnitude more powerful than India so no
comparison now when it comes to
technology Ai and chips we are beginning
our chip making
Journey we're going to have plants
coming up in various parts of India chip
making plants so we're going to be
starting essentially from ABC or maybe
somewhere along the way uh but it's a
good thing at least we are starting but
we are far behind okay maybe like 20 30
years behind maybe 30 years behind the
US and China China is a few years behind
the us and we're going to be like like
20 or 30 years behind China when we
start the chipm pro program so it is
what it is at least we starting now we
could have started in the 1980s but our
government of the time refused and
sabotaged the program for some reason
sabotaged actually uh so we are starting
now so we are far behind in terms of AI
I don't even know where we are in terms
of AI the us we know their AI
capabilities the the
publicly uh the ones that are made
available to the public okay the those
capabilities we we are aware of it's
entirely
possible that the US may
have U us companies military whoever may
have achieved artificial general
intelligence it's possible they may even
have achieved artificial super
intelligence even that could perhaps be
possible we don't know that will remain
under wraps for years maybe
decades so we so that's where the US is
the Chinese also have very good AI cap
abilities uh so they are not they have
not reached the level of the us as far
as we know but they are not far behind
very far
behind what about India when it comes to
AI I don't know if we have even started
doing any AI research I don't know if we
have started then it's not known to the
public we have various Indian companies
that are coming up with AI systems there
was something called cim or something
which turned out to be a chat GPT rapper
that is the sort of lazy stupidity that
Indians are doing okay Indian companies
are just putting wrappers around chat
gbt and they're claiming it's an Indian
AI it's nothing but chat GPT remodified
or repurposed to sound or look Indian to
appear Indian that is the amount of
laziness that we are seeing in India
it's a whole different thing to to
create an AI from
scratch it's possible but you would
need tremendous amounts of the highest
quality gpus Etc Nvidia gpus Etc why is
NVIDIA the the such such a such a
valuable company today because they
their gpus are behind the AI Revolution
so I don't know where India is in terms
of AI I I think we are if we have begun
we we may be just at the beginning I'm
not
sure raban GHA says your thoughts about
anunakis I don't know what that is I've
heard of some Supernatural element or
some
ological tale about something or the
other
I that's the vague understanding I have
something mythological something to do
with uh the Mesopotamian region some
mythological story that came out of
there something Supernatural That's What
I that's that's the vague knowledge I
have about it nothing more than
that
okay shivendu says if China attacks
India with Naval
Army which states do you think it will
choose to enter its Army for Naval
War uh a naval war happens at sea at Sea
it happens in the ocean it doesn't
happen in
States so if a naval war happens between
India and China it will happen maybe in
the Bay of Bengal in the Indian Ocean
region maybe the straight of Mala maybe
U the so-called South China see
somewhere there the Chinese Navy is way
more powerful than Indian Navy so it
will happen closer to the Indian Shores
than to the Chinese Shores so maybe the
state state of malaka region the andan
sea region maybe the Bay of Bengal
region maybe the lakad sea
region that's what I can imagine no
States Naval War doesn't happen on land
it happens at
Sea
okay r Alo Liang bam says I'm M from
Manipur it's been 15 months that Manipur
is suffering and with all the
geopolitical connection going on how do
you think this conflict is going to end
will it escalate
more
look I'll give you the harsh truth
okay things are going to get perhaps
worse before things get better the
Americans have done a regime change in
Burma H sorry in in Bangladesh there's a
regime change happening in Thailand
right now there's a Civil War in Burma
the cookie separatists who want this
this nation cookie land for
Christ uh they have access to unlimited
amounts of arms and ammunition coming
from
wherever okay so they are on the front
foot uh there are certain regions in
India's Far East that are you could say
significantly proi okay without naming
them half of Manipur is under cookie
occupation the indigenous people of
Manipur the
mes and the nagas they are in possession
of let's say the
upper the northern roughly half of
Manipur the M can only only live in
about six or 7% of the land the nagas
can live in the North and that's a
situation
and uh there
is strong us support for the cookies
very strong us support for the
cookies so that's the situation right
now so there is this talk of cukil land
right this artificial Christian Nation
that may be cared out of parts of
Bangladesh parts of Burma and parts of
India so it it may not be an officially
recognized Nation but it will be a large
region that is de facto
controlled by these cookies and
supported by the US so parts of
Bangladesh could be chattogram Etc the
parts of India that could be de facto
cookie land but not officially cookie
land would be the southern half of
Manipur and and large parts of mizoram
perhaps I hope this never happens but
that is the that is what the Americans
are trying to
engineer so considering all this
and considering the fact the US is way
more powerful than India India cannot
even imagine fighting the us or or or
you know entering any kind of
significant conflict with the
us there is a high likelihood that some
of this may
happen so the question is when will the
uh situation in Manipur come back to
normal when will The Suffering end well
that can only happen when the illegal
infiltrators are thrown out of India out
of Manipur
few lack illegal infiltrators cookies
when will that happen I don't even know
don't even know I can't say it may take
20 years it may take
more it takes a lot of time a lot of
logistics Etc to evict to deport I don't
know a few lack individuals they will
refuse to go it they will not go
voluntarily and if they're not going
voluntarily what do you do you have to
deport them by force but they have arms
and ammunition which means they will
fight your government they'll fight your
army they'll fight your armed forces and
if that happens then the great
superpower will say that India is
indulging in human rights
violations and then there is sanction
India then what do you do so that's the
situation India is in right now India
cannot afford to
antagonize the superpower India cannot
afford to go against the superpower
India cannot also on the other hand
India cannot afford to lose its
territory
India cannot afford to lose sovereignty
in Manipur in missor so what does India
do tough times ahead for India tough
times for the government of
India but I think this this uh conflict
this situation will persist for the
foreseeable future it may take at least
20 years for for a resolution to this to
this conflict to to the problem and
please understand please understand my
dear viewers this conflict did not start
in may 2020
3 Manipur was not under foreign
occupation in May 2023
onwards this illegal infiltration was
going on for a very long time started
with the British settling cookies in the
region in the 19th
century and then after and then they
brought in more and more over time in
the 1910s 1920s 1930s 1940s then after
the after Manipur becomes part of India
1949 the government of India who was the
government of India who was ruling which
which party was ruling the country they
brought in more cookies over the next
few decades more and more more and more
they allowed them to come in as refugees
and then they become permanent residents
right so this has been happening for
decades and the indigenous people of
Manipur why were they not protesting all
these
decades there was this view that these
are our brothers and sisters perhaps at
least among some
quarters so you know this situation was
not did not begin in in May 20th 2023
it's been there for a very long
time more than 100 years slowly gradu
gradually progressively getting
worse but only now there is the
understanding of how bad the situation
is so just because somebody has
encroached into your territory and has
settled down and theyve been s have been
they have been on the land for two or
three generations or maybe four
generations doesn't mean they're
citizens they will have to be evicted
there has to be a cut off of an NRC the
cut off should actually be 1891 when the
British illegally occupied
Manipur or 1949 I would say 1891 and
then Deport those who came after that
that should happen but that that won't
happen anytime soon so that's the
situation no easy solutions and no quick
resolution nothing it's going to be bad
for a long
time so Malik s says will Jews face
problems in the West after ethnic
changes there is immigrants in the west
as you say why
is why their Lobby is allowing this Jews
are Jews not influential anymore in the
US are we seeing the Americans pull off
with them
look if there is a significant ethnic
change in the in the west uh it it may
affect the Jews the Jewish people so
there is this significant uh narrative
among in the Islamic world that that
that Israel is occupying Palestinian
land and perpetrating atrocities
committing brutalities on the
Palestinian people all that sort of
thing so there is a very strong
anti-jewish narrative and perception
among the in the Islamic world we know
that Pakistan says Israel has no right
to exist Iran says Israel has no right
to exist in so on right so there is that
now if there is a significant uptick in
the Islamic population of of Europe in
the west these views will become more
and more prevalent in the west that is
Norm normal natural we understand
that so you right Jewish people may may
face more problems in the west as these
ethnic changes happen
and that is to be understood yes so the
question
is why is there Lobby allowing this
well the Jew Jewish I don't know what
Jewish Lobby the Jewish people don't
control France they don't control the US
they don't control Europe as far as I
know some people may claim that way but
do you have evidence to prove that so
look uh
this is happening the Jewish people
certainly are influential Jewish people
are very small but very prominent and
very powerful minority in the US very
influential they are in Hollywood they
are in parts of government Etc clearly
there is something about them that makes
them very
influential they do very well I think um
you know when when you look at the
demographic of the us and we and we take
a look at which part which which
ethnicity in the US is the highest
earning ethnicity it's generally the
Indians right the Indians far surpass
every other ethnicity in terms of the
median income median household income
well I think if you were to where to
show it where to include the Jewish
people as a demographic in that then I
think they would be earning more than
the Indians so they do the best I think
in the US but I don't think that they
control the entire world or control the
us or something something like that you
know so uh yes this demographic the
ongoing demographic change in the west
will
certainly it is certainly possible that
it will make life more difficult for the
Jewish people there there may be more I
don't
know more targeting of the Jewish people
by by the immigrants perhaps one hope
one hopes it doesn't happen but uh
that's uh you have there have been
reports of that to some extent yeah
okay Vishnu Gopi says ksk Invasion
implications so yeah Ukraine war Ukraine
conflict so there's been this Invasion
small Invasion by the Ukrainian military
into Russia the K region it's uh an
ongoing situation initially it was like
the ukrainians have captured a large
amount of Russian territory Etc but now
you are seeing the reversal of
that so
what no implications nothing changes the
Russians are are
prevailing look at the Western media
reports now what's happening in the Kos
region the tide has turned yes initially
perhaps the Russians were caught off
guard maybe the ukrainians had got more
arms ammunition supplies whatever from
the west and they wanted to use that and
they invaded this part of Russia I'm not
sure where it is on the map let's let's
take a look let's try and Discover it so
where is Kur Kursk is
here Kur oblast so this is where the the
uh
Ukrainian uh offensive happened Invasion
let's say they captured a significant
amount of Russian
territory and now the Russians are
pushing back and uh yeah it it this this
won't last
long the Russian military is just way
too powerful for the Ukrainian military
so no no long-term imp a for
this sah says what do you make of the
Saudi King's message to the US of
supporting Israel what could be the
outcomes for both the king and the
Saudi nation's approach look in case you
remember when President Trump was in
power in the US he he had overseen he
had successfully overseen the conclusion
of the Abraham agreements Abraham
Accords which was a peace treaty peace
peace Accord between um Nations like
Saudi Arabia and and
Israel so that was a tremendous
accomplishment that I don't know why the
media wants to not highlight you
know the thing is this Saudi Arabia
wants peace in the region they have no
actual long-term problem with Israel
they are okay with Israel they don't
want to see Israel wiped off the map of
the Earth like Iran does or Pakistan
does Pakistan claims that it that it's
anti-israel but it's a US proxy so M so
Saudi Arabia wants peace in the region
the Saudi regime the Saudi government
understands that their entire nation has
been built on oil wealth but that can't
last forever so they want more
investment of other kinds in the country
they want the economy to grow Beyond oil
Etc and they are pushing hard towards
that for this to happen they need
stability in the region the region
cannot be at War which is which will be
terrible for their country the UAE also
wants the same thing they also want
progress and and and prosperity and
peace in the
region so from their perspective it is
good if there is
peace and both Saudi Arab so Saudi
Arabia obviously if you look at the
history they are uh very strongly
aligned with the
US so that's the
situation uh so I have I have personally
not seen this message of the king of
Saudi Arabia to the US and supporting
Israel but assuming you are correct in
it's accurate then I would not be
surprised about this see recently when
the Iranians launched missiles at Israel
many of those missiles and drones drones
also were were intercepted by the
militaries of Jordan and Saudi Arabia
and perhaps in Iraq also so Saudi Arabia
is on the side of the US Saudi Arabia is
on the side of Israel as well
soft understated way but it's it's there
so that is the
situation theing yadov says please
accept my question do you see any
possibility of World War II with nuclear
detonations by Russia China or NATO or
India Pakistan within the next one
decade okay I think every live stream I
to take at least one question about
World War II so let this be the one what
is World War I how do you define a World
War so you had the first world war the
second world war which were extended
conflicts that happened in large parts
of the world multiple Nations involved
lots of powers fighting each other and
you had conflict in the Seas you had
conflict in Africa you had conflict in
Europe and other parts of the world
that's World War I it was mostly a
European war and in World War II this
spread across the globe India was
involved because of the of the British
who were occupying India Japan was
involved and and much more so that once
again was almost a global conflict there
were battles at Sea battles in air all
that so a world war is generally is
typically a conflict that involves lots
of Nations much of the world and it's a
very severe very deadly
conflict now in today's context if India
and Pakistan go to war is that the world
war it is a World War only if much of
the rest of the world get gets involved
if Indian Pakistan go to war who will
get involved who else the only options
you can think of is probably China and
the US will the Chinese want to get
involved in a war between India and
Pakistan probably they would not want to
get involved they would want to get
involved only if there is very low risk
to them and there is not very low risk
to them if they get involved in a war
against India so if there's a war
between India and Pakistan even if it's
a nuclear war let's say we don't want it
to happen but even if it is
the Chinese won't get involved and the
Americans also probably won't get
involved and even if America gets
involved on Pakistan's side then the war
ends and it's not a World War and before
the US gets involved probably Pakistan
will not no longer exist if it's a
nuclear war so that's not a World War
India Pakistan is not a World War what
about India
China Well India China if they go to war
will Russia get involved no Russia will
stay out of it Russia will very much
stay out of it it is not in their
interest to get involved in a war
between India and China they have their
own huge problems to deal with will the
US get involved in a war between Russia
between China and in and India they will
try to extract more than a pound of
Flesh from India if there's a war so
once again even if it's a nuclear war
it'll devastate both Nations but it's
not a World
War the only possibility of a World War
is if the US and Russia fight each other
what about the US and China what if the
US and China go to war the US will
devastate China China doesn't stand a
chance okay I don't care what the media
narrative what the media narrative is I
don't even care what the American
narrative is the Americans always hype
up China don't they the Americans will
destroy devastate China if there's a war
between the US and China China is no
match to the US not even
close Okay so that's not a World War and
if the US and China go to war the
Russians will want to stay out of it
boss so the only scenario in which a
World War happens is if the US and the
Russians go to war against each other
direct War and the Prelude to that is
NATO going to war with
Russia
okay so that could happen if there is a
significant escalation of the Ukraine
conflict so the the possibility of World
War I is not in Taiwan it's not in India
India Pakistan it's not India China it's
not West Asia or the Middle East it's
Ukraine it could happen from Ukraine and
that's why Ukraine has to be managed
very properly very very carefully by the
west by the Russians as well no stupid
moves and no escalation because if
there's an escalation there could be
nuclear exchange which which will
destroy the entire
planet uh so yeah that's that's how I
see
it right
other says do you think the 60s to 90s
CIA which was famous for regime changes
back after the Bangladesh coup and weak
president like Biden in power do you
think Trump can tackle the CIA the CIA
isn't back it's always been there it's
always been there they didn't disappear
after the '90s they were always around
and they were always capable and their
capabilities are increasing they're
growing they must have penetrated more
countries by now they must have
penetrated the cabinets of more
countries by now like what's his name
says I forget the guy's
name uh so infiltrated they must have
infiltrated various institutions in
various Nations and so on the CIA has
never gone away it's always been there
and they're they're stronger than ever
before Biden is a weak President we know
that but every US president is just like
that some are more some look health here
some look not so old some look very
active vigorous Etc but the real power
is always something else not the US
president so Biden what he has done is
he has finally highlighted the fact that
the US president is not really in power
in the US don't believe that that Barack
Obama was the real guy in Power when he
was in power or Reagan there's always
something deeper and more powerful
behind the scenes that is in power in
the US and that's what everyone calls
the Deep state
so that's the deal now do I think Trump
can tackle the CIA
no nope Trump cannot tackle the
CIA Kennedy tried to tackle the CIA John
F Kennedy he tried to tackle the CIA you
know what happened to
him uh Trump was very fortunate he was
not
1963 while he was President he was
almost 1963 this year a month or so ago
right he was very fortunate to
survive uh I think the only way he
becomes president again is if is if he
kisses the ring so to say but I still
think it's more likely that Kamala
Harris will will be the next US
president so it doesn't
matter whether they capable of not of
ruling a country what matters is who if
they are is that they are on the right
side okay
Shri V says what's your take on
Bangladeshi Hindus and ringas the
refugee crisis don't you think that the
Refuge crisis is is engineered to
decelerate the Indian economy yes of
course every crisis that is engineered
in India is engineered to hamper India's
economic growth and to hamper and and to
and to compromise India's cohesion as a
nation to compromise the government of
India's ability to administer the nation
to create fissures and divisions
artificial fishes and Division in India
in in the Indian society and if such
exist such divisions already exist
because of the past Thousand Years Years
of occupation then you want to make
those divisions and Fishers wider and
you want to exploit that to destabilize
the country to compromise the country
and essentially to rule the country from
outside by proxy eventually that's the
objective so um any refugees that come
into India any illegal infiltrators with
that enter India whether they are
illegal bangladeshis whether they are
ringas whether they are cookies they're
all part of this entire drive this
entire uh project to compromise India to
infiltrate penetrate India and to make
India
completely
transparent to to certain foreign powers
and eventually the the objective
naturally will be to put to have a proxy
government coming power in India which
is a proxy of a foreign
nation that that's the deal now what's
my take on Bangladeshi Hindus they are
undergoing a
genocide and I'm sure that most of my
Bangladeshi viewers who may be watching
will disagree and they may feel that
there is no
genocide well first of
all in 1971 the population of Hindus in
Bangladesh was what 20% 20% plus today
it's 7.5% what
happened after the pakistanis left
Bangladesh did anything
change and right now I have seen all
kinds of
horrible uh reports about what's
happening to Hindus right now in
Bangladesh so there is definitely clear
targeting of Hindus not just by random
mobs but also by by the police in
Bangladesh and by the government so it
may slowly simmer down but there is
deliberate definite targeting of Hindus
so
yeah shagun choa says what do you think
about our thoughts creating our
world yeah well that's a philosophical
question we observe the world out here
right but how do we know this world
really
exists after all we know that we have
sense we we perceive the world through
our sense organs we have five senses
right we have sight we have smell we
have taste we have audition ears and we
have the sense of touch through these
five senses we perceive the world and we
paint we create this picture of the
world around us so I'm wearing a red
t-shirt of this blue color gradient over
here these books and other stuff over
here all this I
perceive through my
senses now these
senses they they bring the information
of the outside world into our brain
where it is processed and they bring
this information through nerves through
nervous signals through
impulses that are that travel in our
neural circuitry so the eyes have the
optic nerve that crosses itself behind
behind the eyes and then goes into the
brain there is an auditory nerve and
there's the Opthalmic system Etc so
there are nerves that take these signals
and impulses into the brain
so we are relying on electrical
electrochemical
signals to create this image that we
have of the world and our entire world
view now what if that's not
reliable what if actually there's no
Universe out there it's only our brain
that exists in the entire universe and
somehow we are perceiving these these
signals that are not true what if that
is the case
so this is a a school of thought called
solipsism I believe that you are you
possibly are the only uh being that
exists in the world your brain is the
only thing that exists in the world and
you are somehow getting all the signals
that there is that are convincing you
that there this entire world out there
and so many people out there and so many
relationships and so on but actually
it's only you that's the solipsistic
world
view so I don't know about that look we
have it's it's an interesting thought
experiment it's interesting to look at
the world that way because it makes
sense logically that it could could
perhaps be true even though the
probability of that being true is very
low but yeah that's something you should
you can consider from the perspective of
of
logic uh so yeah and the the other thing
is maybe you can create you can create
the future you want so what is that
thing Ronda something that the secret
means you you manifest your future and
all that so I don't know about that how
true that is but it's always good to
believe that that you can change the
world that you can manifest whatever
future you want that gives you
confidence and maybe you maybe maybe
that's true who knows I don't know
there's no scientific evidence that it's
true but maybe it's true because science
can't explain everything science is very
inexact science cannot ex explain 95% of
the universe so yeah perhaps that may be
true who
knows Anisha says attacks on Bangladeshi
Hindus are still going on every day as
we speak that is correct that is correct
no matter what the media narrative is in
Bangladesh no matter what people are
made to believe in Bangladesh but
attacks are still happening they're
going on as we
speak hopefully it stops hopefully Mr
Muhammad unus can if he has any power at
all he can stop it if he wants to don't
know if he
will
um okay abinandan abinandan Das says the
land between the southernmost tip of
tripura in the Bay of Bengal is also
narrow can India put pressure on that
choke point to deter the US from
occupying the St Martin's Island please
show your thoughts so here's what we are
talking
about you go to India's Far East you
have tripura right tripura as you can
see agala for example I'll come come to
the point that you're making is on the
border between India and Bangladesh if
you want to land in agala you have to
overfly
Bangladesh where's the
airport
um where is aala airport okay it's
somewhere on the on the on the
border so agala is on the border between
India and Bangladesh now the
southernmost tip of uh tripura over here
uh
if we calculate the distance from there
to the Sea it's about 25 kilm very small
distance so it's not a choke
point uh okay let's go back to the map
and this island that we're talking about
is over
here it's uh actually off the coast of
Burma but it's a Bangladeshi
Island so I don't understand why IND
India did not ensure that there is a a
connection between the sea and India's
Far East tripura should have access to
the Sea so I don't know why we we didn't
do that I don't know why we did not
expand the chicken's neck in 1947 when
we accepted the map of the partition of
India but okay that's all in the past
the point
is ideally the Chong region the
chattogram region should have been part
of India and if there is is any attempt
to change the the map in the demographic
of the of this region which is actually
ongoing then perhaps if if push comes to
shove then India should take back the
chram
region uh in which case it'll be great
for the Indian Far East because we will
we will have access to the sea from
there but when it comes to the US trying
to occupy the St Martin's Ireland
there's nothing India can do about it
it's a matter between the the new B
regime which is a puppet of the US and
the Americans so most likely within a
year or two the Americans will take
possession of the St Martin's Island
probably they must
already perhaps be perhaps have boots on
the ground over there it's
possible
okay Lisa Rose says what is what really
is valkism how is it affecting people
today especially in
India uh
look earlier it was called being a
social justice Warrior
sjw then it was called being
woke uh in the future they they may call
it something else but what is it it is
nothing but an but a continuation of of
the Marxist ideology so Marxism has
evolved over time it was all about the
dictatorship of the proletariat and the
upliftment of the common man and woman
and all workers of the World Unite and
all that nonsense okay but act that was
the stated objective of Marxism but
actual actually what Marxism does is
that it enables a very small group of
people to come to power and to stay in
power which is seen in various communist
regimes the poit
bureau that you had uh that you have in
China and the USSR Etc and so on now
Marxism has infiltrated the West and
it's a great way of creating divisions
in society and destroying societies
destroying cultures and
civilizations so um Marxism is has been
part of the US Academia since the 1950s
1960s and now it's everywhere and uh the
Democratic party is essentially uh a
left leaning
party which means that they they they
espouse what you call sjw uh ethos and
the voke ideology which is ESS
essentially about
uh it's it's about essentially
destroying
Society um so how does it manifest
itself first of all it in the 50s and
60s it manifested itself as an attack on
men an attack on the patriarchy because
so you have to couch whatever you're
doing in very uh moralistic words so you
say that the patriarchy has been
oppressing women for thousands of years
so you doing something good by attacking
the patriarchy that's what you say so
then you go after men and you
essentially emasculate men you men you
render men powerless in society so
feminism used to be about equality now
it's about women first and Men down
that's how it has
transformed in the west so you you
disempower the men in society which is
50% of the of the population and then
you say that Society is not equal enough
yet so then you want gay rights lgbtq
rights which is fine which is fine but
then you put all that front and center
and then you go for Trans rights and
what not so everybody wants to be trans
now and then people regret that and
there's also the attack on the on on
Christianity in the west so it doesn't
matter what religion a certain Nation
follows there's no right or wrong in
that but what religion does is that it
gives every every
person a moral and ethical framework
what's right what's wrong what's good
what's bad how to move forward in life
so you don't have to think most people
can think unfortunately thinking is hard
work thinking is painful most people
just want to be told what to do they
want to be told what's right and what's
wrong so that they can just do things
without thinking so that's what religion
has historically done in every society
so Christianity used to be the framework
of Western Society now it is being um
you know it's being dismantled so that's
what we see in the US most people
identify as atheists most people most
people say that they not Christian and
so on that's what you're seeing
increasingly in the west so overall what
it does is that it destroys the family
system it destroys religion it destroys
the moral and ethical framework of
society it atomizes Society it reduces
the unit of the society to the
individual instead of the family and
then you can manipulate the individual
in whichever way you want by hooking
them up on drugs on Pharmaceuticals on
the media on entertainment and you can
get them to do whatever you want so they
become essentially automatons robots
sheep at your
disposal and that obviously benefits the
big corporations it benefits whoever is
in power and government and so on so
that is what's happening and now they're
trying to export it to the
east now Russia won't accept it good for
them but Chinese will not accept it good
for them our Persian
friends won't accept it good for them
but we in India we are a fully
transparent permeable Society it's
coming into India while the academic
system by
Academia U why the entertainment
industry while the media so it's it's
dangerous for India eventually it'll
it'll end up destroying India as well if
you're not careful that is the
point okay
artillery chavda does AC work Al or do
you have any researchers editors
thumbnail makers Etc uh researchers I
can never hire because I cannot rely on
anybody else's research I had a I had
some editors and thumbnail makers but I
fired them all maybe I will get some
more going forward
maybe shaswat mukarji says uh what's the
importance of Diego Garcia for Americans
I've made a whole video on that but uh
I'm happy to answer once again Diego
Garcia Diego Garcia is is over here it's
called the British Indian Ocean
territory uh it is illegally occupied by
the
British and the British have handed it
over to the Americans so what is this
thing first of all so it is part of the
heos archipelago which is which is part
the southernmost part of the Maldives
chos Ridge okay so it's actually part of
the lakwe Maldives
region so it should actually well
technically it should be part of morus
okay but it historically is part of the
Indian Ocean region and India's sphere
of influence now this island Diego
Garcia it's an
ATL and it
has uh an Air Force Base which can
handle the heaviest and most powerful
American strategic bom numbers fighter
planes whatever it also has a
naval uh based where is
it uh where is the naval
thing probably
here probably inside over here okay
wherever it is I will not go deep and
look into the details but it it has a
naval base that is capable of
accommodating aircraft carriers which
are the biggest and most powerful
powerful ships in the US Navy so from
Diego Garcia the Americans can project
power anywhere in the Indian Ocean
region what do you mean by projecting
power it means that you have the
capability to destroy everything in the
region if you wish which means everybody
behaves everybody does what you say that
is projection of power so that's the
importance of theog garia it's a region
it's it's a it's a base from which the
Americans can project power in the
entire region the Americans acquired
this in 1973 now why 1973 why not before
that they acquired this in 1973 because
of their failure in
1971 how did they fail in 71 they were
they failed to prevent India from
liberating Bangladesh from east from
Pakistan so India successfully
transformed East Pakistan into
Bangladesh the Americans wanted it to
remain Bangladesh the Americans wanted
sorry they wanted it to remain East
Pakistan the Americans were supporting
the genocide of Hindus done by the
pakistanis and India prevented that
successfully so that's why the Americans
realize that they need a base from which
they can genuinely project power in the
region and that can if required be used
against India so that is the importance
of Diego Garcia for the
Americans Grim so bad says by the time
we become a 10 to 15 trillion dollar
economy we will already be divided well
that's the
objective that's the objective of the
great powers or great power or great
Powers whatever you want to call it they
would like us to be broken up balkanized
before we can ever reach our
potential so a nation as large as India
if it reaches its potential and
especially with the history that we have
we're going to be the world's largest
economy eventually 2070 2100 whenever
but we will get there that is just who
we are so how do you prevent that from
happening you balkanize the nation you
create artificial divisions among the
people you make people hate each other
the people of each state should hate
each other and you you artificially
re-engineer the demographic of the
nation bring in foreign religions that
are deeply an antithetical to the
indigenous culture and then you create
all kinds of problems in the in the
country and then you have the country
break up into pieces that is the
objective okay so these big powers are
not our friends
they want to see India balkanized and
they are doing it quite openly actually
subnational diplomacy and engaging with
various opposition political parties and
all that stuff stay out of our Affairs
but they won't so that is the objective
and if we are strong enough and
resilient enough and if our government
is strong enough and resilient enough
then we will be able to prevent this
from happening so I would say let's not
be so cynical let's not be so
pessimistic let's not have such a
defeatist
attitude let's be optimistic I think we
have a tremendous amount of strength and
resilience too within ourselves and
let's be optimistic and let's work
towards preventing such a thing from
happening all of us in our own
way that's what I would
say Nas says like the session guys show
your support thank you so much ni
everybody like And subscribe I never say
that do I everybody like And
subscribe thank
you
um
okay Aman bahuguna says what are the
similarities between ancient Indian
civilization and Sumerian and Babylonian
civilizations look one of the so when we
talk about Mesopotamia we're talking
about the
land the fertile land between two rivers
what two rivers you ask you have to go
to Iraq for that and in Iraq you have
two rivers the Tigris and the Euphrates
so if you go to
Bagdad you will find that there is this
river that flows to Bagdad which is the
Tigris okay that's one River and then
you also have the Euphrates which is
this one
here and the land between these two
River Rivers the
fertile land between these two rivers is
the Mesopotamian region
Mesopotamia and that is where you have
these civilizations the Sumerians the
Babylonians the
acadians and so
on and these civilizations existed I
don't know 5,000 years before today uh
3,000 BC roughly or something like that
okay and since then plus or minus
obviously it didn't start suddenly in
3,000 B around that time okay now what
were the Civil so so when we had the
sarasti Hindu phase of our
history that's when you also had these
civilizations and there was significant
contact between us and Them us as an
Indian India and the the Mesopotamian
region and you also had ilam marashi and
so on so forth lots of things to unpack
there I'll not go into the details now
the question obviously is what are the
similarities between our civilization of
the ancient times and the Mesopotamian
civilizations that existed over various
periods of time first of all first
similarity polytheism we have always
been a polytheistic Society we still
are memia also was polytheistic whether
it's suia the acadians the Babylonians
Etc
polytheistic that's the first
similarity what else second
similarity enjoyed trade I think we
traded a lot with them uh we had trading
outposts in presently Oman Etc and so so
there was a lot of trade
so I'd say these are the similarities
polytheism is the very very strong
Stark uh similarity which you don't have
there today the entire region is
monotheistic today so it was
polytheistic deeply
polytheistic and there was goddess
goddess worship and much more so I think
that's the major similarity and you have
all these carvings and frescos of lions
and and and and
uh human animal hybrid gods and all that
so that's you know that's the
polytheistic uh that's the way the
polytheism manifested itself over there
so that's what you
have
okay Aman tripati says does India have
classified Technologies like we see
conspiracies about uaps UFOs and other
Technologies of the US look if tech
techology is classified I am not part of
the Indian government How will I know
about it tell me I'm just a guy I am not
associated with the government of India
I don't have access to classified
information I don't have access to
Secrets if we have classified
Technologies well it will please me very
much I'll be very happy if we do if we
are secretly developing AI systems
Quantum Computing systems UFO systems or
whatever UAP systems futuristic aircraft
or whatever else the they they talk
about what Ancient Aliens
right all that stuff look if we are if
we have such programs it will please me
very much I'll be very happy but I don't
have any information about that so can
say sorry can't answer the
question other says can Trump end the
Ukraine Russia War do you think if Trump
was in power this war would have never
happened um
it's it's difficult to answer look Trump
would very much want to end the war now
the question is this how does the how
can the war
end so to answer that question you to
ask
yourself what are NATO's objectives in
this War and what are Russia's
objectives in this war the war was
started by Russia the special military
operation which was launched by
President Putin under his command under
his order on his orders in February
2022 so why did he launch the operation
and what was the objective of this
operation the objective of this
operation is first of all to denn naify
Ukraine remove all Nazis whichever way
whichever way secondly to ensure that
Ukraine becomes permanently neutral not
pro NATO not anti- Russia permanently
neutral and thirdly to affect a regime
change in KV these are the objectives of
Russia now what are the objectives of
NATO the objectives of NATO the
objective of NATO is very clear that
they want to have Ukraine become a NATO
outpost on Russia's borders and they
want to have their puppet regime
continue in Kia whether it's under Mr
zalinsky or somebody else doesn't matter
the person doesn't matter it's just a
mask it's just a
figurehead so that's NATO's objectives
so as long as these two objectives are
starkly different the war continues
until one power prevails and Russia is
going to Prevail the way things are
going so how do you stop the war so how
can Trump end the war he can only end
the war either by defeating Russia in
Ukraine which won't happen not going to
happen so if that doesn't happen then
how do you end the war it's by giving
Putin what he wants which means NATO
withdraws from Ukraine NATO takes out
zalinsky and puts him in California or
whatever
Hollywood or whatever there's a change
in Ukraine and Ukraine becomes neutral
so that would mean a defeat for NATO
Will trump be allowed to do that by who
by those who really rule the US I doubt
it very much so I don't think Trump can
end the Russia Ukraine war I don't think
so and if Trump was in power the war
would have still
happened Trump would have tried to
negotiate meet Putin whatever but uh I
don't think if if he went too far
ahead in in uh accepting Putin's
terms would not have worked for him
would have been a very bad outcome for
him let's just say it that
way so I don't think Trump can end the
war without giving Putin what he
wants
okay R chobra says when when will the
immigration crisis in in Europe ever end
will the Indian people people who are
planning to go there as tourists
students workers Etc and the Indian
diaspora be safe in the Chava index okay
the immigration crisis in Europe will
end when the when Brussels decides that
it ends so the real power in Europe is
the European Union the European Union is
an organization that takes our
sovereignty from the individual nation
states that are its member states the EU
from Brussels its headquarters decides
what are going to be the immigration
policies economic policies Etc much more
in Europe in the EU region the shenen
region and it's the EU from Brussels
that is behind this immigration crisis
and who actually rules the EU and
controls the EU it's the US okay it may
not be visible it may not be apparent
you may say it's all false but that's
what's going on it's been that way since
1945 the real power in Western Europe is
the US now so the immigration crisis is
not going to end it's going to perhaps
get worse unless the US decides let's
stop it why would they stop it they have
clearly have some kind of objective
behind this so they'll keep keep it
going um so I don't see it ending
anytime soon uh will Indian people who
are planning to go there as tourists
students uh workers whatever and those
who already live there the diaspora will
they be
safe uh hopefully they'll be safe uh you
are seeing a an escalation of of
undesirable incidents in the west
attacks on natives attacks on white
people uh
rioting uh noo
zones uh violence against women and much
more youve seen all that terrorist
attacks you've seen a lot in France Etc
so I think overall over time Europe is
becoming less safe for the locals as
well as for for
visitors um I'm not sure if Paris is
worth visiting anymore Paris used to be
the number one destination in the world
tourist destination in the world right
I'm not sure if it still has that old
charm if it even still has that old
identity that Paris used to have you
know it may have changed a lot it may
not even feel like the old Paris anymore
um the point is over time Europe may
become more
dangerous for visitors
it's possible I I don't know I hope it
doesn't happen I hope Europe stays safe
and peaceful and charming and whatever
else it used to be but it looks like if
the immigration continues and more and
more people come in who have no who who
don't have
any who don't believe in the European
ethos and culture or whatever it is in
the local country then things will
change and things will be in these
countries will become overall less safe
for the locals and for
tourists uh that's how I see it going I
hope I am wrong I hope I'm wrong but
yeah overall things don't look good for
Europe
definitely yes some very intelligent
people on Twitter have been asking this
St Martin's island is only three square
kilometers how will a US Naval Base be
built there and that's a very good
question it's a very good question so
let's compare it with for example dieo
Garcia okay British Indian Ocean
territory so what is the if if we if we
disregard the the the empty space in
between which is the the Lagoon how
large is this this is 24 kilm from here
to there from
here and from here to here 16 kilomet
so much of that 20 25 by 50
how much is it it's about 300 something
Square
kilm 300 plus square
kilometers and if you subtract the the
Lagoon which is of course very
useful then it could be perhaps 50
square kilometers or maybe 30 square
kilometers and and this island as you
rightfully point out St Martin's island
is a fraction of that roughly three
square kilometers
what can you do
there what can the Americans build here
well you can certainly build an air
strip over here it is actually ideally
shaped for an air strip you can have an
air strip you can have a military
base and you can
have A2 ad capabilities what is A2 ad
you ask A2 ad means
anti access area deny
it's a very strange weird sounding
military term A2 ad
anti-access area denial what does it
mean what does it mean to have an A2 ad
bubble it means that you place very
dangerous very scary missiles on this
island and these missiles have a certain
radius in which they can take out
anything and by putting these missiles
here you can interdict a very large area
of land or Sea from hostile
forces you know what this
does it essentially can choke
off can essentially make this entire
area
uh forbidden for the Indian Navy or the
Chinese Navy
whoever that's what you can do with a
powerful military base here so you don't
need 30 square kilm 50 square kilm
3 square kilm is
enough you have an Air Force Base here
you have an air strip which is about
let's see let's see how long this is
from here to here it's 4.7 kilo almost 5
kilometers so you engineer this you can
reclaim some land you can you can build
a 4 kilometer air strip that can
accommodate the the most powerful
strategic bombers you can put missiles
over here large quantities of Miss ises
and you can have training a training
base where you can train terrorist sorry
uh Insurgent sorry Freedom
Fighters Etc so you can do a lot in this
place okay please understand you can do
a lot in this place from here the
Americans can actually cut off the
malaka street if they want because they
have theiles that can do it they can
also interdict large part of the Bay of
Bengal to the Indian Navy the Chinese
Navy and they can essentially cut off
China's access to the Bay of Bengal
through this region because through
Myanmar China had
access there's a lot you can do with
three square
kilometers so I know lots of very
intelligent people have asked this
question but here's the answer there's a
lot you can
do mclen says PM Modi said it's time for
the UCC uniform civil code do you think
it can really implement it as he doesn't
have a full majority simple answer is it
will depend on his Coalition partners
if they are okay with it it may
happen if if they disagree then it may
not happen depends
depends all
right uh what
else why are ysf say do you think India
has a master plan to take the northern
part of Bangladesh of the future which
would be so beneficial to India such as
solving chicken neck transportation to
the sisters Etc I think eventually it
should happen Okay this is obviously
historically Indian Territory you take
rangapur Etc the northern part then you
widen the chicken's neck that that
becomes no longer a liability and you
can have better access to the Far East
of of
India also you would want to have the
chatram area reincorporated into India
it should never have been part of his
Pakistan or Bangladesh and that would
give India the Far East of India the
states over here tripura missor Etc
access to the Indian Ocean and some
Geniuses will say it's the Bay of Bengal
not the Indian Ocean well hello the Bay
of Bengal is part of the Indian Ocean so
Indian Ocean so yes eventually it should
happen but right now it won't happen
because the Americans are waiting for
India to make any stupid moves
eventually it will happen but not not
yet not
yet okay
um artillery chavda says what's the
purpose of of the president of India why
not get rid of it or is it some for some
political
Pastime I don't know what's the purpose
of of a of a ceremonial
post every every every single aspect or
facet of the governance Machinery should
have a clear purpose which takes the
nation forward and is beneficial to the
nation I don't know why we need to have
a president in this country when the
president has no power is
not I mean what's the purpose I don't
understand maybe I'm asking a question
as if I'm a 13-year-old but I'm not sure
what the purpose is it's a purely
ceremonial position look at the nation
of the US they don't have a single
ceremonial position unless unless you
understand that the US president and
vice president don't really have any
power but okay so my point is we we
don't I don't know why we need these
things these are leftovers from the
British
Raj um when we became a dominan of the
UK
1947 dominan status then we had this
constituent assembly that determined
what kind of structure the Indian
governance should have and the they they
formulated the Constitution and so on so
forth and they decided that the Indian
uh system should be a complete replica
of the British system a by Camal uh
Westminster Parliament system and
because the British of the House of
Lords we needed to have a rajas SAA
why do you need a rajas SAA why why why
why can't it only be the Lo SAA the the
representatives of the people the
elected representatives of the people
why do we need a rajasa you don't trust
the elected representatives of of the
people enough do do you and then you
have and in the in the UK you have the
king or the queen so we also needed
something like that so we created the
post of the president it's simply
slavishly copying your former Master
that's what it is I don't know why we
need to have all that why can't we have
a completely indigenous system of our
own but we don't have it so I don't see
what's the purpose I see there's I think
there's no purpose
actually Lisa Rose says what's the
biggest secret you know about the world
well you see lisar Rose the thing about
Secrets is that you should never tell
them and I am really good at keeping
secrets so I can't reveal Secrets I can
speak about what I can speak there are
things that I can't speak about truly so
I I can't speak about those things but
yeah there are things that can't be
spoken about openly there are things
like
that
okay
um okay Kazi ofab says power of the
president is realized during realized
during a state of emergency well the
president yeah you're right technically
the president of certain powers
technically um in a state of emergency
the president takes gets some extra
Powers Etc but generally see look I'll
tell you what we've had only one state
of emergency in India right 1975 or
something around that time when prime
minister Indira Gandhi declared a state
of emergency now who was the president
at the time does anybody remember I
don't remember what great power did that
president have the real power was the
Prime Minister Mrs Gandhi wasn't it so
technically according to the books the
president has some apparently some extra
powers during emergency but in the real
sense of the world as history has shown
us has demonstrated the real power was
prime minister Indira
Gandhi okay so there is a see my friend
aab there's a gigantic difference
between the world of textbooks in the
real
world so according to the textbooks and
according to the Constitution
also the president has certain technical
Powers
technically but in the real world as the
75 emergency
demonstrated the real power was Mrs
Gandhi and her government so there you
have
it Vidant rate says what's the future
future of China can India become as
developed as China in terms of
infrastructure GDP Olympics Etc look I
hope the future of China is wonderful
and prosperous I have absolutely nothing
against China they are an ancient
civilization 3,000 years old okay 3,500
years old they've learned a lot from us
and overall they' have been very
friendly with India it's only since 1950
since the 50s that India and China
become adversaries because of Chinese
actions because of the action of the
Chinese Communist party before that
India and China were never ever enemies
we had excellent relations so I think
China hopefully has a great future I
know there's a demographic disaster
coming
up uh the total fertility rate has
declined
precipitously it's one of the lowest in
the world and there's there's a tough
time coming up for China but hopefully
I'm talking about a 500 year window here
I hope China does well I hope genuinely
hope China prospers and does
well um as long as it doesn't happen at
the expence of India
so and I hope yeah so that's that's how
I see now can India become as developed
as China I think we can become way more
developed historically we were always
the larger economy historically we have
always been a next net exporter of
culture to China China has learned so
much from us and absorbed so so much
from us I'm not saying everything that
China has achieved is because of us not
by by no
means but overall we were always the Big
Brother truly speaking okay we are the
older civilization even president sh
Jinping has accepted that India is older
than
China uh so India can become way more
developed in the future we have to
regain our historical
position for which we had for thousands
of years as the world's preeminent
civilization most advanced civilization
and most in the largest economy it's
certainly is something we can achieve
and right now we are far from that right
now we are a small
economy $4 trillion economy a small
power and the powers that are currently
larger than us will be very jealous and
they will not want India to rise so we
will have
to essentially run the gauntlet and and
go through a very difficult phase if we
are to regain our position but no great
thing happens easily you have to work
very hard for it you have to struggle
for it struggle hard so we will have to
do that so we have a very tough 20 years
coming up for us and if we get do things
right then we will become Unstoppable
but 20 years it's going to be tough for
us everybody will be up against us
essentially lakshman KD says will US
meddling of India and meddling in Indian
Affairs and meddling in Chinese Affairs
will it bring India and China together
in some
aspects is good question yes it could
happen uh if they go too far they will
end up pushing India and China in the
same
camp it doesn't mean that India and
China will become friends it means that
we will
temporarily seize
hostilities uh India will demand that
China
should um agree to quickly rapidly
demarcating the
border and once that happens there's no
real
problem but it it doesn't mean that
everything is fine so if the Americans
apply too much pressure on India and
China it may and it probably will end up
doing that and then India could open up
its economy to to Chinese Investments
and all it will be great for the Chinese
economy it'll be good for India Etc and
we to do it carefully it could happen
there is a scenario in which this
happens and we may perhaps be close to
that scenario that's as much as I would
say right
now okay
okay
um D Singh says can imch come into
existence in the near future imch is the
India middle east Europe trade Corridor
it was supposed it it was signed off on
in October or something last year 2023
during the G20 Summit that was happened
that was held in New Delhi in India I
was
there and the Saudis wanted this to
start
immediately but
then it was September October and then
you had the terrorist attack by Hamas on
Israel and then you have the escalation
of the conflict in the region and that
has thrown cold water over the project
so if the situation in the Middle East
region in West Asia stabilizes iMac can
still go ahead it will have to it will
essentially connect Mumbai Mumbai and in
the western part of India or essentially
the whole of India with the Arabian
Peninsula by sea and by air then you
will have ports in the Arabian Peninsula
that will take Indian goods and and the
other way around by rail across the
Saudi Arabian Desert and that will cross
over Via Jordan into Israel perhaps
Lebanon and then from there by sea into
Greece bypassing turkey and from gree
into the rest of Europe so it's
connecting India with Europe and Europe
with India both ways that's a great
project and it would have emerged as a
competitor and a great alternative to
China's belt and road infrastructure so
right now it's not happened because of
the conflict that's raging in the West
Asia region if the conflict subsides
this project could go ahead but yeah
that's the situation that we are
currently
in okay I will take maybe one or two
questions more that's it geopolitical du
say do you see any sign of she losing
control in China well China is opaque
the system is opaque and you can't
really tell what's going on inside so
from where I am I don't see any signs of
she losing control in China from time to
time there is this narrative in the
media that sh Jinping has been deposed
or he has been arrested by the military
or there's been a coup or whatever I
don't know how they come with these
stories but uh I don't see any of that
happening so if it happens it may happen
without
warning and let's take one more question
um okay what what do
I Surendra Gupta says what's the
relation between Russia and bear Russia
is see every every every nation is
depicted as an animal right in some in
in cartoons and all so the US is this
evil looking Eagle right very Stern and
very harsh eagle and India is either an
elephant or a tiger it's typically the
tiger some but the Chinese like to
portray India as as a sleepy elephant
the Chinese are the dragon and Russia is
the bear why is it because Russia is
full of Bears and the Russians are they
know how to handle Bears so in India
like we have we know how to handle cats
and dogs and it's normal for us and in
Gujarat it's t it's lions in Russia you
have Bears so bears are almost like dogs
in Russia that's what they say so yeah
so the bear is essentially the symbol of
Russia and there's this very famous
cartoon Masha and the Bear
I think it's Russian
propaganda I think Masha is Europe and
Russia is the bear and they're saying
that hey Europe don't worry the bear
will take care of you the bear is not
dangerous bears are dangerous I'll tell
you that I'll tell you what bears are
some one of the most dangerous animals
on the planet they look so cute and
fluffy and soft and round and clumsy but
believe you
me bears are dangerous even tigers in
India stay away from bears
so don't
ever believe that bears can be petted or
cuddled or whatever if you see a bear
put a lot of distance between you and
that guy because most Bears won't do
anything hopefully but they are capable
of incredible violence very powerful
beasts anyway I don't know why I'm
talking about bears so uh there you have
it okay I'm going to end this session
over here thank you so much for all the
questions lots of different questions we
took and I know that there are lot lot
more questions going on but I'm going to
end it over here and I'm going to see
you tomorrow in tomorrow's live stream
in which I'm going to take questions
from the comments so if you have more
questions there's still time to to
comment on on my Channel with your
question and if the question is good
enough and if it interests me and if
it's relevant I will take it so yeah
that's it for today thank you so much
for for participating for your questions
and I will see you very soon in the next
live stream until then take care and as
always keep raising your standards